export const quizData = [
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: 'In Figma, which keys can you press to activate the Frame tool?',
    options: ['F or A', 'Ctrl + F', 'Shift + F', 'Alt + F'],
    correctAnswer: [0],
    explanation: 'You can create a frame by clicking the Frame tool or pressing F or A.',
  },
  {
    type: 'boolean',
    question: 'In Figma, you cannot nest frames inside each other.',
    options: ['True', 'False'],
    correctAnswer: [1],
    explanation: 'You can nest frames inside each other in Figma.',
  },
  {
    type: 'multiple',
    question: "Which of the following shapes are available in Figma's Shape tools?",
    options: ['Rectangle', 'Line', 'Arrow', 'Ellipse', 'Triangle'],
    correctAnswer: [0, 1, 2, 3],
    explanation: 'Available shapes include Rectangle, Line, Arrow, Ellipse, Polygon, and Star.',
  },
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: 'In Figma, which shortcut aligns objects to the left?',
    options: ['Alt + A', 'Alt + D', 'Alt + W', 'Alt + H'],
    correctAnswer: [0],
    explanation: 'The shortcut for aligning left is Alt + A.',
  },
  {
    type: 'multiple',
    question: 'Which of the following statements about resizing layers in Figma are true?',
    options: [
      'Holding Shift keeps the same aspect ratio',
      'Holding Option resizes from the center',
      'You can change width and height values in the properties panel',
      "Clicking 'Constraint Proportions' allows disproportionate scaling",
    ],
    correctAnswer: [0, 1, 2],
    explanation:
      "To scale proportionally, click 'Constraint Proportions'; otherwise, it scales disproportionately.",
  },
  {
    type: 'boolean',
    question: 'In Figma, you need to leave the design tool to adjust image exposure and contrast.',
    options: ['True', 'False'],
    correctAnswer: [1],
    explanation: 'Images can be edited directly within the design tool after importing.',
  },
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: "In Figma, which tool would you use to change an object's background color?",
    options: ['Fill', 'Stroke', 'Effects', 'Layers'],
    correctAnswer: [0],
    explanation: "Click on 'Fill' to start customizing the background.",
  },
  {
    type: 'multiple',
    question: "In Figma's color picker, which methods can you use to change the color?",
    options: [
      'Click the color wheel',
      'Use the eyedropper tool',
      'Input the HEX code',
      'Choose from preset colors',
    ],
    correctAnswer: [0, 1, 2, 3],
    explanation:
      'You can change the color by clicking the color wheel, using the eyedropper tool, inputting the HEX code, or choosing from preset colors.',
  },
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: 'Which grid is commonly used for mobile design?',
    options: ['8-point grid', '10-point grid', '960 grid', '12-column grid'],
    correctAnswer: [0],
    explanation: "For mobile, it's common to use an 8-point grid.",
  },
  {
    type: 'boolean',
    question: "In Figma, it's not possible to apply gradients to objects.",
    options: ['True', 'False'],
    correctAnswer: [1],
    explanation: 'Figma allows you to replace solid colors with gradients.',
  },
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: 'In Figma, which shortcut aligns objects vertically to the center?',
    options: ['Alt + V', 'Alt + H', 'Alt + A', 'Alt + S'],
    correctAnswer: [0],
    explanation: 'The shortcut for aligning vertical centers is Alt + V.',
  },
  {
    type: 'single',
    question: 'Which statement best describes the benefit of using grids in Figma?',
    options: [
      'Grids help apply complex effects to objects',
      'Grids ensure elements fall on clean pixels, avoiding half pixels',
      'Grids automatically align text layers',
      'Grids allow instant image editing',
    ],
    correctAnswer: [1],
    explanation:
      'Setting up a grid ensures all elements fall on clean pixels, avoiding half pixels as much as possible.',
  },
];
